

Heudon da Silva Reinaldo

Almere Muziekwijk, Netherlands

E-mail: heudon@gmail.com

Phone: +31 6 38231816

ABOUT

I'm a brazilian software engineer based in Almere, with 10 years of experience. I'm always looking for the best balance between pragmatism and clean solution. One quote I bring to my life and my work is that, if you think that you are better than no one, you are already better than a lot of people.

Tech skills: OOP, DDD, SOLID, PHP, Symfony, Zend, Python, Django, Javascript

WORK EXPERIENCE

Recharge.com

June 2020 — Feb 2021

Tech Lead

Role Summary:

Anti fraud & payment team got splitted into two teams, and I became the tech lead of the anti fraud team. After that, the anti fraud application became more autonomous to grow decoupled from payment domain, allowing fraud analysts to create more rules for handling fraud, decreasing the false positives around 40% and the fraud numbers around 20%.

Company domain: E-vouchers (netflix, amazon, bol...) and online mobile topup

Pin points:

- Responsible for modeling the domain of the application with team members
- Responsible for creating ci/cd pipelines

Tech stack:

Python 3, Django 3, celery, MySQL 5.6, Redis, docker, Sentry, Grafana & Kibana, New relic, aws (ecs, s3, ecr), RabbitMQ, github, gitlab ci/cd, Atlasian tools

Recharge.com

Nov 2019 — May 2020

Senior Software Engineer

Role Summary:

As part of the payment & anti-fraud team in the company, we had to deal with approximately 1 payment per customer for every second, between 5 and 200 euros each of them, from more than 10 payment providers across the world. While in the anti-fraud side, for each payment done, we had to run an anti fraud pre-check and reply in < 0.5s.

Tech stack:

- **General:** docker Sentry, Grafana & Kibana, aws (ecs, s3, ecr), RabbitMQ, github, gitlab ci/cd
- Anti Fraud: Python 3, Django 3, celery, MySQL 5.6, Redis
- Payment: PHP 5.5, PHP 8, Zend Framework 1, MySQL 5.5, Memcache

SCRiBBR

Feb 2018 — Oct 2019

Heudon da Silva Reinaldo

Senior Software Engineer

Role Summary:

I was responsible for the main application which allowed editors to proofread academic thesis from students. It had a database of thousand of freelancer editors, and internal supporters could find the best suitable Editor to proofread those student documents and deliver within the deadline chosen by the student himself.

Company domain: Proofreading of academic documents (thesis, articles)

Pin points:

- Responsible to move application from vagrant to docker
- Responsible to reduce from 1 minute (without cache) into 2 seconds the main dashboard used by support team, rewriting it with proper queries, indexes, and reading model

Tech stack: PHP 7.3, Symfony 3.4, MySQL 5.6, 8, Sentry, docker, RabbitMQ, Redis, github, gitlab-ci, circle-ci (migrated).

Gfk B.V

June 2016 — January 2018

Senior Software Engineer

Role Summary:

I was part of the team responsible for maintaining a B2B app, in which companies could create dynamic surveys forms (php), collect millions of answers (mongoDb) from their customers, create their own dashboards using our platform in Vue, which called our php api's, therefore using some php extension generated by another team.

Company domain: Marketing surveys

Pin points: Implemented a POC in one week reading batch of tweets from given topics, running sentiment analysis on them, and generating charts with result.

Tech stack: PHP 5.3, 5.6, 7.1, Mysql 5.3, 5.6, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Git, Jira, Docker, Redis, Memcache, ReactJS.

Vox Tecnologia

January 2012 — May 2016

Medior Developer

Role Summary:

Maintained their application to allow 10 brazilian chamber of commerce spread around 10 brazilian states to manage every single process related to any type of company in brazil, since from opening new companies, changing addresses, until closing them.

Tech stack: PHP 5.3, PHP 5.6, PHPUnit, PgSql, Zend Framework 1, Symfony 3, Jquery, lamp, git

Acadeone Sistemas

Jan 2011 — Dec 2011

PHP Developer Trainee

Role Summary:

Maintained a project to manage schools.

Tech stack: PHP 5.3, PHP 5.6, PHPUnit, PgSql, Zend Framework 1, Symfony 3, Jquery, lamp, git

EDUCATION

Specialization in Software Engineering

October 2014 — April 2017

Heudon da Silva Reinaldo

Bachellor in Information Systems

January 2008 — June 2012

Instituto de Educação Superior da Paraiba

PERSONAL LINKS

- https://github.com/kbca
- https://www.linkedin.com/profile/view? id=AAMAAAsaumsBIWWuF_bAytwdra4c4_JcJ66sXMA
- https://stackoverflow.com/users/9565406/heudon-reinaldo?tab=profile
- https://www.zend.com/en/yellow-pages/ZEND022219

Heudon da Silva Reinaldo